Nikki Peel

Front End Developer

Michigan, USA

(810) 577-2639

nikkipeel.com nikkipeel.dev@gmail.com

LinkedIn Github Codepen

I'm a junior Front End Web Developer with extensive experience in customer satisfaction. I began my career in restaurant service as a Line Cook and quickly grew in to a management position. As a Manager, I was required to maintain a high level of empathy and willingness to resolve conflict with both staff and clientele. I made the personal decision in 2015 to begin learning the skills necessary to transition into a more flexible career that would better accommodate my disability.

My education at Baker College and Mott Community College focused primarily on Graphic Design and Business Communications. I found great programs online such as Udacity, Codecademy, Udemy, and FreeCodecamp to begin my journey into web development. I've completed several bootcamps and have earned certifications for Responsive Design, Front End Frameworks, and ReactJS. More recently, I became motivated to study web accessibility and learn how to build projects that fully comply with WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines).

On most days I can be found creating custom components and landing pages on Codepen for practice and testing purposes. I really enjoy using front end frameworks such as Bootstrap or Google's Materialize to jump start my projects. I'm also experienced with writing semantic HTML, creating custom styles with CSS, and using vanilla Javascript. I have a working knowledge of Adobe products such as Illustrator, Photoshop, and XD. Moving forward, I'd be interested in furthering my current knowledge of Javascript frameworks such as React and Angular.

I'm currently seeking a remote role where I can collaborate and grow as a developer. I'd love to become the next addition to your team and contribute my creative skills!

EXPERIENCE

Collage.com, Michigan — Customer Satisfaction Representative

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Providing live online support to Collage Customers
- Using Freshdesk, Freshchat, Google Suite, and Aircall for support
- Finding and applying solutions to account or order problems

Freelancer, **Michigan** — Front End Developer

Feb 2017 - PRESENT

- Creating responsive websites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and frameworks (Bootstrap, Materialize, Semantic UI)
- Customize Wordpress sites and improve SEO
- Testing and offering solutions for accessibliity concerns

Restaurants (various), Michigan — Server, Line Cook, Manager

Apr 2006 - Apr 2019

- Ensure proper sanitation, food preparation, and equipment maintenance
- Resolve guest concerns in an efficient and courteous manner
- Create and adhere to a structured plan for staff to include assignment of workstations and development of a food preparation list
- Perform regular office duties such as: manage cash, catalogue data, order product, create schedules, and open/close the store

EDUCATION

Deque Systems — Web Accessibility

JUN 2020- PRESENT

Studying WCAG (Web Content Accessibility Guidelines) to earn Web Accessibility Specialist certification

Udemy, Online — Web Development, Front End

SEP 2019 - PRESENT

Web Developer, Advanced Web Developer, Advanced CSS/Sass, Advanced Javascript, React, and Vanilla Javascript bootcamps

Codecademy, Online — Web Development

FEB 2017 - SEP 2018

Courses completed as part of the Web Development Path: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, AngularJS, PHP, Python

Baker College, Michigan — *Graphic Communications*

FEB 2007 - MAR 2009, FLINT

Business, Marketing, Advertising, Communications, and Graphic Design courses completed